anand.ravneet099@gmail.com

+44 7570009636

RAVNEET ANAND

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior Fullstack Developer based in London with over 10 years of experience in software engineering. Demonstrates persistent problem-solving skills and enjoys taking on new challenges. Adapts easily to changing circumstances with a strong focus on collaboration. Looking to leverage skills and experience to contribute to the growth and success of a company.

SKILLS

NodeJS

••••

React

••••

React Native

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$

Next.js

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$

Tailwind CSS

Typescript

••••

FaaS(AWS Lambda)

AWS CodePipeline

Test tooling

SQL

••••

NoSQL

LANGUAGES

English

••••

French

•••00

Punjabi

....

Hindi

••••

Urdu

••••

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

APR 2024 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer, Compute and Cultivate, London, UK

- Lead the design and development of high-performance web applications using React, Tailwind CSS, and Next.js, focusing on optimizing user experience and enhancing front-end aesthetics and functionality.
- Oversee the architecture and implementation of mobile applications leveraging React Native and Expo, ensuring seamless cross-platform compatibility and high-quality user interfaces.
- Drive the integration of React and Next.js in building SEO-optimized, server-side rendered applications, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement metrics.
- Collaborate closely with product teams and stakeholders to deliver tailored solutions in web and mobile development, meeting precise business needs and customer expectations.
- Mentoring and coaching junior software engineers to foster their growth and development in technical skills and product knowledge
- Doing regular code-reviews in order to deploy quality code

JAN 2022 - MAR 2024

Senior Software Engineer, Perlego, London, UK

- Effectively collaborated with a cross-functional team to successfully deliver projects on time and within budget
- Enhancing the security of the server requests using encryption that helped prevent illegal downloading of books, upholding publisher contracts
- Designed microservices using Lambda, Node.JS, MySQL, Redis, ECS, S3, SNS and SQS
- Added features like Read-aloud to the React based reader platform that increased subscription by 32% and raised user's CLTV by 30%
- Helped migration to a new deployment strategy using AWS tools to accelerate efficiency

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u> Github

HOBBIES

ΑI

Travelling

Learning new languages

MAY 2019 - DEC 2021

Tech Lead, SopraSteria, Toulouse, France

- Worked extensively on fine tuning the complex SQL queries and database performance resulting in a notable 40% reduction in pageload time
- Implemented NodeJS based microservices from scratch while migrating windows-app to web-app
- Facilitating cross-cultural communication between the French and Indian teams to ensure smooth collaboration
- Managing project timelines and ensuring deliverables are met on time for clients like Airbus, ST Microelectronics and more
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to develop and implement innovative technical solutions for clients in the aerospace and semiconductor industries

JUN 2013 - MAY 2019

Senior Software Engineer/Software Engineer, SopraSteria, Noida, India

- Leading team on some modules of the application
- · Gathering the requirements with the on-shore team
- Implementation of new functionalities in the applications

SIDE PROJECTS

Vocabo!

A React-Typescript-based language learning extension for Chrome and Firefox that helps reinforce vocabulary retention. This extension allows you to pin down newly learned words along with their meanings in your language. These words will then appear randomly on web pages, providing timely reminders of their meanings and enhancing your learning experience.

EDUCATION

AUG 2008 - DEC 2012

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communications, Guru Tegh Bahadur Institute of Technology, Delhi, India

Passed in first division

IMMIGRATION STATUS

UK Work Rights

Needs a visa sponsorship